So let's do a trick here function, which is, this is the following. So let's talk about in-order traversal of trees, right? So what's that? So for this example that we have there, an in-order traversal is the following. So just go there. So you go, you firstly, the in-order traversal
of this one would be, firstly, the left, the leftmost child of all the tree, and then its parent, and then the leftmost child of the other sub-tree of the parent, which here is just going to be six. But if you had like six, and then something else, then it's going to be that something else, and then we go like this. And then you go up another level, and then it's nine.
And then the leftmost child of the sub-tree of nine, which is going to be this one, then its parent, and then again, the leftmost child or the leftmost leaf in the right sub-tree of that parent. So it would be 17 here, and then that's it.
So an in-order traversal of this tree would be 1, 3, 6, 9, 11. Basically, and the intuition is basically, if that tree is a binary search tree, the in-order traversal is the sorted list of elements in the tree.
What is a binary search tree? I assume that you know that, but I would just say it. And the binary search tree is a tree where every node is greater than all nodes in its tree.
It's left sub-tree, and every node is strictly smaller than all nodes in its right sub-tree. So that's basically the in-order traversal. So how do we define a function that does that recursively? So let's do that again.
So in-order, again, it's going to be a recursive function of binary trees, so it should cover the same two cases. So in-order of leaf, and in-order of the non-leaf case, node A and R.
So in this case, we have the anti-list. As you remember, the tree returns a list, the functions are returned a list, and the non-antit B for the non-antit tree case will return another list, and that list should be the...
If you remember, we go to the direction of the recursion code as follows. You go to the leftmost sub-child, and then to the parent, and the leftmost sub-child of the parent, which uses that.
And then to the parent, and the leftmost sub-child, and then to the parent, and the leftmost sub-child.
So how would that work here?
Recursively the way we would represent that is simply so you would say in order of L
appended with just the parent and
then in order of
R and then this one will keep going to the left
Most and then back up and then to the right and then then this one also go to the left most and then
So to get if we give us the correct
List so let's try and see that from how that function would actually
Deal with the stream we have there, right? So
If we would evaluate that function, right? So in order of
What was the tree again? So
In order I will just copy it
So in order traversal of that tree that we have there is going to be the same as in
Order of the left sub tree, which is 3
appended to the singleton list which is 9 of the parent and then
appended to in order of the right sub tree, which is
17 and the reason we did that was because okay, this is a non empty tree
So what that what that did to us is that it took us in this equation and then the equation we just are
Lined the following the equation. So here we have in order of the left and then the parent and then
The right so we have an order left parent and then right and then we keep recursive we doing that
So I'll just do it a few more times
That would give us and then we evaluate this one this term
So have an order of
One and two leaves as children prove that right thing
ended with a singleton list has three appended with in
order of
Tree that has just six and all of that is appended with nine
Which is appended with in order of
again, where would that take us?
So let's just do this one. So again here we going to so the first time we evaluated this
then now I'm going to evaluate that so we have here in order of
Leaf I'll just write the leaf like that
appended with
one and then appended with in order of another leaf
Then that's appended with three and that's appended with in order
six
Okay
The whole thing is appended with
With that okay, and then I will now evaluate this one
So maybe let me just write that one. So that's a bit clearer. So that is
Appended with nine
appended with in order of
17 so then they in order of that. This is going to give us the empty list and then
appended with
one and then
I'll just evaluate this as well. So this will be an empty list and then
appended with
three
appended with so as you can see
How the list synthesis is taking place here. So let me just prove that so
Then we're going to do that and then this is going to like this will evaluate to just one
Because you're pending one with two empty lists and then you have three and then you have the rest. So
Just go back. So here that's the correct order because you have one and then three and then six and then nine
So now basically is how you will
Proceed with that. So
Perhaps I'm going to do a few more steps. So here we have three and then
So now we're done with this, you know, we evaluate this this one
so in order of
leaf in order of leaf and then nine in
order of
13 11
17 and that would give us
one
three
Appended with six with the rest. So perhaps as an exercise
finish this
G on your own. So now
That's basically how we define
Functions of arbitrary types, of course, you know, you can do the same for the leaves the the tree that has its content in the leaves
So now let's go to an Isabelle
demo of how to define recursive functions on
These algebraic other types